<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>SU LABS</title>
		<link>http://startup.singularityu.org</link>
		<atom:link href="http://startup.singularityu.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		<description>Growing startups applying exponential technology to address humanity’s grand challenges.</description>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 14:03:21 -0700</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 14:03:21 -0700</lastBuildDate>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Singularity University Startup Accelerator Welcomes Cohort 2</title>
				<link>http://startup.singularityu.org/blog/05-03-2016-cohort-two.html</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 14:29:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<author>labs@singularityu.org (SU LABS)</author>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://startup.singularityu.org/blog/05-03-2016-cohort-two.html</guid>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The team at Singularity University’s SU Labs is proud to announce our second Accelerator class. After scouring the globe, reviewing hundreds of startups, interviewing scores and vetting dozens, we finalized a list of four companies for our second class. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--break--&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fieldready.org/&quot;&gt;Field Ready&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - 3D Printing humanitarian supplies (medical, infrastructural, etc.) in the field. Created by two founders with a wealth of foreign aid and engineering experience, the team has long standing projects in Haiti and Nepal and are opening a lab in Turkey to deal with the Syrian refugee crisis. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.impactvi.com/&quot;&gt;Impact Vision&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; -  Using hyperspectral imaging technology (cameras detecting multiple bands of color) to tackle the $1 trillion issue of food waste (1/3 of the global food supply). The technology provides much better quality control in  the food supply chain, from producer to retailer. The team is using  artificial intelligence to analyze food freshness and contaminants,  and is further evolving  to become a platform for hyperspectral data. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://junobiomedical.com/&quot;&gt;Juno Biomedical&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Using electro-regenerative technology for brain repair. Juno has developed a technology (Celltech) which can affect the neurological signal between cells in order to direct stem cells to damaged parts of the brain. The team is building on decades of research and has the backing and support of prominent neuroscientists. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mzptec.com/&quot;&gt;MZP Tech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Applying microfluidics to the development of smart and affordable medical diagnostic tools. The team  developed the “Blood Microviscometer”, a device that analyzes a single drop of blood in just a few minutes and could radically affect the diagnosis of cardiovascular conditions. MZP Tech is  currently running pre-clinical trials in conjunction with two hospitals in Argentina and has attracted a lot of interest from neonatologists, cardiologists and hematologists both in Argentina and the US.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/2016-05-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Singularity University Accelerator Cohort 2&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeking to move away from standard accelerator models, our aim for the program is to provide a hyper-tailored experience for the companies. The guiding principles for this program are to: Network, Expand and Accelerate. The Networking element is the focal point for this cohort. The strength of our collective community will be the deciding factor in the success of our startups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Expand portion of the program aligns the startups with the exponential thinking model at Singularity University. During the first two weeks of the program, we will have expert speakers highlight the impact of up and coming  technological trends affecting our startups. We are optimizing each session for a specific, tangible outcome and have built a workshop model of 1 speaker / 1 outcome. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the concurrent 6 weeks, the companies will integrate their learnings into the building phase. We will pull back structured programming and devote individual time for startup development. This will serve the overarching goal to Accelerate our ventures.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to have amazing companies in our cohort and look forward to a great program!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Singularity University Accelerator: Weeks 3-5 Recap</title>
				<link>http://startup.singularityu.org/blog/11-11-2015-accelerator-week-3-5.html</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 07:49:18 -0800</pubDate>
				<author>labs@singularityu.org (SU LABS)</author>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://startup.singularityu.org/blog/11-11-2015-accelerator-week-3-5.html</guid>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;With the SU Labs Accelerator rounding week 8, we wanted to fill you in on the mid-program learnings during weeks 3-5. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--break--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following our Bootcamp and Prototyping focused weeks, our startups dug into baseline necessities for scaling up their companies. Week 3 focused on developing financial and team building acumen. Our startups heard from Jim Cook, CFO of Mozilla and co-founder of Netflix about Financial Structuring. The participants later heard from a panel of VCs about vetting and evaluation.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To bolster team cohesion we hosted Gayle Young, former Chief Culture and Talent Officer at Wikimedia, to speak to our companies on co-founder dynamic and team-building.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent week 4 on developing sales and marketing best practices. We hosted Tracy Demiroz (early stage/stealth marketing expert) for one-on-one deep dives with companies. Later in the week Tim Chou, one of the pioneers of Cloud based services, spoke on the trick to quickly closing enterprise sales. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To bookend the weeks, we hosted Salim Ismael, author of Exponential Organizations (Frost &amp;amp; Sullivan 2014 Innovation Book of the Year) for an intimate dinner. Salim spoke about the exponential technologies which are closest to disrupting major industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the weeks recap below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-4iK4X0cQOY?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Gayle Young on Team Dynamic – The Most Overlooked Startup Killer</title>
				<link>http://startup.singularityu.org/blog/11-11-2015-team-dynamic.html</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 07:49:18 -0800</pubDate>
				<author>labs@singularityu.org (SU LABS)</author>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://startup.singularityu.org/blog/11-11-2015-team-dynamic.html</guid>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Develop your product. Nail your pitch. Raise funding. These phrases comprise 90% of the advice entrepreneurs receive. An equally crucial and rarely talked about piece is the importance of team and specifically co-founder dynamic. In the heads down world of startups, it’s easy to overlook the importance of effective communication and building a cohesive team culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--break--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make sure our founders are set up for success, we hosted Gayle Young, the former head of Culture and Talent at Wikipedia to speak on healthy team dynamic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/C_FPLLSeljM?showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>An Elusive Metric: Kevin Starr on Measuring Impact</title>
				<link>http://startup.singularityu.org/blog/11-04-2015-measuring-impact.html</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 07:49:18 -0800</pubDate>
				<author>labs@singularityu.org (SU LABS)</author>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://startup.singularityu.org/blog/11-04-2015-measuring-impact.html</guid>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Our 2015 Accelerator startups span a variety of industries. We have teams engineering organisms to generate electricity for early-detecting water contaminants. We have teams building the world’s largest community of blind people by crowdsourcing eyes to the visually impaired. Among others, we also have a company which is doing great work in treating mental illness with an emotionally-intelligent AI. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--break--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite their different areas, the binding tie of our Singularity University startups is devoting their work to impact a billion people. To ensure they are designing to solve these large problems we had Kevin Starr, the Managing Director of the Mulago Foundation and guru on impact evaluation, speak to our startups. Check out the video below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hJIof3I6Ibw?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Countdown to Demo Day: 4 Weeks till Launch</title>
				<link>http://startup.singularityu.org/blog/11-03-2015-4-weeks-until-launch.html</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 08:34:29 -0800</pubDate>
				<author>labs@singularityu.org (SU LABS)</author>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://startup.singularityu.org/blog/11-03-2015-4-weeks-until-launch.html</guid>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Daylight savings. An extra hour worth of incentive to get up early, stare down your inbox and move your product forward. Our startups took the extra time and devoted it to their pitch training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--break--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our companies are lucky to be coached by Bill Joos of Go To Market Consulting. Bill spent over seven years as the VP of Entrepreneur Development at Garage Technology Ventures, an early-stage venture capital firm that he helped co-found with startup guru/author Guy Kawasaki. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/2015-11-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Teams in Deep Discussion&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The presentations have come a tremendously long way thanks to Bill’s guidance. He has taken them through the entire pitch journey from the handshake pitch (what you say after saying hello) to the napkin pitch (conceptualizing your mission) to the proper on stage presentation. Our entrepreneurs have refined their message all while working on product and funding developments. They are excited to spread their message with the world on 12/1!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Singularity University Accelerator - Week 1 &amp; 2 Recap</title>
				<link>http://startup.singularityu.org/blog/10-21-2015-week-one-and-two-recap.html</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 05:25:40 -0700</pubDate>
				<author>labs@singularityu.org (SU LABS)</author>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://startup.singularityu.org/blog/10-21-2015-week-one-and-two-recap.html</guid>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;With our inaugural startup accelerator in full swing, it is time to look back at the first two weeks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an action-packed first week (our “bootcamp” week) where our startups went through a series of workshops and lectures – all with the aim to prepare them for the weeks ahead, the teams moved into the rhythm of weeks 2-9. For the next couple of weeks our entrepreneurs will spend time on building their product, forming partnerships and pitch to investors; and lectures, workshops and lots of social interactions with our amazing speakers &amp;amp; mentors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--break--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give you a taste of what life at the Singularity University Accelerator looks like (and to learn from some of our mentors), watch this video summarizing the first two weeks of the program:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/C0uw7zVgxaQ?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our first week we had Tom Chi, former Experience Lead at Google [x], lead our teams through a rapid prototyping session:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JW4v24qu0K4?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here Tom shares his deep insights with us:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OTy1k6Mb7_M?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Singularity University Startup Accelerator is Off to a Great Start</title>
				<link>http://startup.singularityu.org/blog/10-10-2015-startup-accelerator.html</link>
				<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<author>labs@singularityu.org (SU LABS)</author>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://startup.singularityu.org/blog/10-10-2015-startup-accelerator.html</guid>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Last week Monday we launched Singularity University’s inaugural startup accelerator. Seven teams from all around the world joined us here on the NASA Research Park campus in the heart of Silicon Valley for the next ten weeks to learn, explore, grow and build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--break--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will report here on their progress, stories and key learnings. Our amazing mentors will share their key insights with you in short videos. And you can follow the action live on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/su_labs&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/su_labs&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To kick things off – &lt;a href=&quot;http://singularityhub.com/2015/10/02/taking-flight-meet-the-startups-of-the-2015-inaugural-su-labs-accelerator/&quot;&gt;read up on our seven portfolio companies&lt;/a&gt; and watch a video recap of day one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sjg78zNGv9E?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Matternet starts testing package delivery with Swiss Post</title>
				<link>http://startup.singularityu.org/blog/07-10-2015-matternet.html</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<author>labs@singularityu.org (SU LABS)</author>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://startup.singularityu.org/blog/07-10-2015-matternet.html</guid>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In partnership with Matternet, Switzerland’s postal service announced this week it had begun testing parcel deliveries by unmanned drones. Postal service executives showed off the drones for the first time on Tuesday and said initial tests of the machines’ post-delivery abilities would run until the end of July. Swiss Post, which is cooperating on the project with Swiss WorldCargo – the air freight division of Swiss International Air Lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--break--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/2015-07-10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Matternet Drone&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, Swiss Post said it expected to mainly use the drones in emergency situations, which could “involve bringing supplies to an area that has been cut off from the outside world following a storm.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company also stated that “another realistic possibility is the urgent transport of consignments with the highest priority, such as laboratory tests,”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This partnership represents great early market validation of the Matternet autonomous drone delivery system. We are proud of the team and look forward to their next update!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/jul/08/swiss-post-begins-testing-postal-delivery-by-unmanned-drone?utm_content=buffer6fda6&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer&quot;&gt;Full story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Nexleaf in Fast Forward Accelerator</title>
				<link>http://startup.singularityu.org/blog/07-08-2015-nexleaf-in-fast-forward-accelerator.html</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<author>labs@singularityu.org (SU LABS)</author>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://startup.singularityu.org/blog/07-08-2015-nexleaf-in-fast-forward-accelerator.html</guid>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to announce that &lt;a href=&quot;http://nexleaf.org/&quot;&gt;Nexleaf Analytics&lt;/a&gt; will be joining the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ffwd.org/&quot;&gt;Fast Forward Accelerator&lt;/a&gt; for non-profit companies. Nexleaf manufactures and deploys wireless sensors to ensure vaccines don’t spoil during storage or transport. By leveraging the global network of cell phones coupled with low-cost sensors, they allow public health organizations with limited resources to achieve large-scale impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--break--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fast Forward Accelerator unlocks the power of the tech community to tackle social issues. From poverty, to education access, to improving health, to environmental degradation. Seeing an industry gap in supporting tech nonprofits, Fast Forward provides financial and human capital to help scale these technology solutions and maximize impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are very excited for the Nexleaf team; keep up the great work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ffwd.org/announcing-fast-forwards-2015-cohort/&quot;&gt;Here&amp;#39;s the announcement.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Kicking Off The Graduate Studies Program</title>
				<link>http://startup.singularityu.org/blog/06-22-2015-kicking-off-the-graduate-studies-program.html</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
				<author>labs@singularityu.org (SU LABS)</author>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://startup.singularityu.org/blog/06-22-2015-kicking-off-the-graduate-studies-program.html</guid>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;We are &lt;strong&gt;extremely&lt;/strong&gt; excited to kick off our 2015 Graduate Studies Program (GSP). Out of hundreds of applicants, Singularity University chose 80 finalists to attend the 10 week long experience. The GSP participants will spend the first five weeks in intensive learning modules, where our faculty will teach them about exponential tech. The curriculum will feature prominent speakers such as Guy Kawasaki (Apple’s first chief evangelist) and Tom Chi (creator of Google Glass). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--break--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The participants will spend the following five weeks pairing off into groups in the team project phase. This time will be focused to building a product which uses exponential tech to address a Global Grand Challenge. Companies such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://mttr.net&quot;&gt;Matternet&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://madeinspace.us&quot;&gt;Made in Space&lt;/a&gt; were built in previous GSP programs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobel Peace Prize winner Muhammad Yunus kicked off the GSP festivities with a rousing speech about the power of socially geared development. He spoke of his journey in establishing the Grameen Bank (and pioneering micro financing), developing the Grameen phone (mobile for the rural poor) and curing night blindness among children in Bangladesh. Mr. Yunus spoke about the transformative power of technology and encouraged the GSP 15 class to develop projects with a billion people in mind. We are incredibly grateful to Mr. Yunus for making the time to speak to our GSP class and are excited for the coming weeks ahead!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Oo6EBWETkC4?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
